Max Luper

Raleigh, NC, 27603 Phone: (919) 339-0283

Email: mluper.official@protonmail.com

Summary

Experienced full-stack developer who is comfortable with any language or framework. I place a heavy emphasis on code quality and development process efficiency. As a team member, I tend to be the go-to person for information and help, and for mentoring junior developers.

Experience

Instancy, Lead Developer 09/2019-12/2019

The company was establishing a US-based development team in hopes of scaling up their application infrastructure and building a client base in North-American and European markets.

- Developed OAuth API for use in an authentication server
- Audited security and reported on potential vulnerabilities
- Built a content-delivery API using Azure cloud storage
- Evaluated and planned solutions for quality issues that were significantly impacting development turnaround

ECS Limited, Developer 01/2017-02/2019

My team and I rewrote a core legacy application that drove the company's material testing services. The release was lauded as the most successful in their recent history.

- Designed a database schema and model that could accommodate changes made to the ASTM standards since the original application
 was built, and wrote the import scripts to translate legacy data to the new system
- Wrote a RESTful API for programmatic access
- Built a suite of web applications for data entry and maintenance
- Built reporting and billing services and confirmed the application integrated smoothly with existing systems

ECS Limited on contract through Robert Half, 01/2016-12/2016

My team and I revamped their user-permissions system to manage user access to application features. They needed configurable default permissions based on the job title and roles of the user, with the possibility of granular overrides for edge cases and special situations.

- Built the database schema and wrote deployment data scripts
- Built RESTful API for read/write access and to serve up user permissions and rules
- Built simple and fast client-side utilities for checking permissions on each page and API call
- Built suite of UI tools to allow network administrators the ability to manage user permissions

<u>Headway Workforce Solutions</u>, Developer 12/2012-05/2016

Headway's major services are recruiting, staffing, and payroll, with a specialization in retail and short term employment.

- Fulfilled development needs to maintain existing systems and satisfy client needs
- Rewrote large parts of the time entry and approval system
- Rewrote large parts of the payroll management system
- Standardized C# data classes and created a utility library to simplify read/write operations

Headway Workforce Solutions, Jr. Developer 01/2012-12/2012

Headway's systems were heavily SQL driven, with over a thousand stored procedures used for data read/write functions as well as serving as the business layer for some applications.

- Fulfilled development work to maintain the existing systems and satisfy emerging client needs
- Audited the database for unused tables, views, and procedures
- Eliminated dynamic SQL
- Began standardization of stored procedure naming and formatting

Headway Workforce Solutions, IT Support 10/2010-01/2012

During my time working as IT support, I taught myself the skills needed to help with programming tasks, leading to a promotion to Jr. Developer.

- Performed general IT support duties for maintaining equipment and assisting users and clients
- Analyzed and resolved data issues in MSSQL database
- Identified and resolved minor bugs in C# AspNet WebForms application
- Wrote Crystal Reports documents for online paperwork features

Education

UNC Asheville, B.A. Philosophy